Edward Butscher Collection of papers on Sylvia Plath, 1918-1976
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
- Series II. Writings, 1945-75
  - SYLVIA PLATH
    - Poems S (18 items)
      - "The Spring Parade": photocopy from The Phillipian 1945 Apr (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Spring Sacrament": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Star Over the Dordogne": photocopy from Poetry 1962 Mar (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Stillborn"
        See: "The Surgeon at 2 A.M."
      - "The Stoic": typescript, photocopy 1949 (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Stopped Dead"
        See: "Winter Trees"
      - "The Suitcases Are Packed Again": photocopy from Seventeen 1953 Mar (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "The Surgeon at 2 A.M.": printed version 1971 Sep (Box-folder 5:131)
    - Poems T-Z (22 items)
      - "Temper of Time": typescript, photocopy 1950s (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Terminal": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Three Women"
        See: Box 5, folder 138
      - "The Times Are Tidy"
        See: Box 6, folder 147
      - "To Ariadne": typescript, photocopy 1949 Jun 10 (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "To Miss Cox": photocopy from The Phillipian 1946 Nov (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "The Trial of Man": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Triolet Frivole": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Tulips at Dawn": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Twelfth Night": photocopy from Seventeen 1952 Dec (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Twilight": typescript, photocopy 1949 (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Two Lovers and a Beachcomber by the Real Sea": typescript, photocopy and photocopy from Mademoiselle 1955 Aug (Box-folder 5:132)
        See also: "Resolve"
      - "Valentine": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Vanity Fair"
        See: "Spinster"
      - "Voices": typescript, photocopy 1950 (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Wallflower": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "When the Stars Are Pale and Cool": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "White Phlox": typescript, photocopy 1949 (Box-folder 5:132)
        See also: "Question"
      - "Widow"
      - "Wild Geese": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "A Winter Sunset": typescript, photocopy and photocopy from The Phillipian 1946 Feb (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Winter Trees": printed version from Mademoiselle 1972 Mar (Box-folder 5:132)
      - "Winter Words": 2 typescripts, photocopies undated (Box-folder 5:132)
    - Prose A-D (9 items)
      - "About a year ago I was babysitting..." holograph with drawing, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "All the Dead Dears": photocopy from Gemini 1957 summer (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "America! America!": photocopy from Punch 1963 Apr 3 (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "Among the Bumblebees": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "And Summer Will Not Come Again": photocopy from Seventeen 1950 Aug (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "The Bike Ride"
        See: "Star Island"
      - "The Breakwater"
      - "Cambridge Letter": photocopy from The Isis 1956 May 16 (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "The Dark River": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "The Day Mr. Prescott Died": photocopy from Granta 1956 Oct (Box-folder 5:133)
      - "Den of Lions": photocopy from Seventeen 1951 May (Box-folder 5:133)
    - Prose E-H (5 items)
      - "An Evening at the Hoftizers": holograph, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:134)
        See also: "Star Island"
      - "The Fifteen-Dollar Eagle": photocopy from Sewanee Review undated (Box-folder 5:134)
      - "The Garden Party": holograph, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:134)
      - "Gramercy Park": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:134)
      - "The Green Rock": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:134)
      - "Heather Birds Eyebrows"
        See: "Initiation," early draft
    - Prose I-M (8 items)
      - "In the Mountains": photocopy from Smith Review 1954 fall (Box-folder 5:135)
      - "Initiation": photocopy of early draft and printed version in Seventeen 1953 Jan (Box-folder 5:135)
      - "The International Flavor": photocopies of 2 typescript drafts 1950 summer (Box-folder 5:135)
      - "It's All Yours": photocopy from Seventeen 1952 Oct (Box-folder 5:135)
      - "A Morning in the Agora": photocopy from The Phillipian 1947 Feb (Box-folder 5:135)
      - "The Mothers' Union": photocopy from McCall's 1972 Oct (Box-folder 5:135)
    - Prose N-Z (11 items)
      - "New England Summer": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "The New Zealand spinach...": typescript and holograph with drawings, photocopy 1950 (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "None But the Lonely Heart"
      - "Party Girl"
      - "The Pink Comb"
      - "Snow Blitz": typescript undated (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Spring Song": photocopy from The Phillipian 1946 Apr (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Star Island": holograph with drawings, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Sunday at the Mintons'": photocopy from Smith Review and photocopy from Mademoiselle 1952 (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Superman and Paula Brown's New Snowsuit": photocopy from Smith Review 1955 spring (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Tea With Olive Higgins Prouty": typescript, photocopy 1955 Jul 19 (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Two Gods of Alice Denway": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "Victory": photocopy from The Phillipian 1947 Apr (Box-folder 5:136)
      - "The Wishing Box": photocopy from Granta 1957 Jan (Box-folder 5:136)
    - Thesis "The Magic Mirror": 2 photocopies 1955 (Box-folder 5:137)
    - "Three Women": photocopy of radio script and audience research report 1962 Jul-Sep (Box-folder 5:138)
  - ABOUT SYLVIA PLATH
    - Alvarez, A. "Sylvia Plath: A Memoir": photocopy from New American Review and review of The Savage God from Boston Review of the Arts 1972 Jun (Box-folder 6:139)
    - Davison, Peter. "The Heroine": typescript 1970-72 (Box-folder 6:140)
    - Duffy, Martha. "The Triumph of a Tormented Poet": printed version from Life 1971 Nov 12 (Box-folder 6:141)
    - Hardwick, Elizabeth. "On Sylvia Plath": printed version from New York Review 1971 Aug 12 (Box-folder 6:142)
    - Horowitz, Israel. "Some God Got Hold of Me": printed version from The Village Voice and "Success in Spite of Suicide": printed version from The Village Voice 1971 Oct 28, Nov 4 (Box-folder 6:143)
    - Klein, Elinor. "A Friend Recalls Sylvia Plath": printed version from Glamour 1966 Nov (Box-folder 6:144)
    - Krook, Dorothea. "Recollection of Sylvia Plath"
      See: Box 4, folder 121
    - Lameyer, Gordon. "Letters from Sylvia": typescript, photocopy and printed version 1975-76 (Box-folder 6:145)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol. "One for Life, One for Death": printed version 1972 Nov 19 (Box-folder 6:146)
    - Plath, Aurelia Schober. "Preface" to Letters Home
      See: Box 5, folder 124
    - Robins, Corinne. "Four Young Poets": photocopy from Mademoiselle 1959 Jan (Box-folder 6:147)
    - Roche, Clarissa. "Sylvia Plath: Vignettes from England"
      See: Box 4, folder 122
    - Rosenstein, Harriet. "Reconsidering Sylvia Plath": photocopy from Ms. 1972 Sep (Box-folder 6:148)
    - Scholes, Robert. Review of The Bell Jar: printed version from The New York Times Book Review 1971 Apr 11 (Box-folder 6:149)
    - Sigmund, Elizabeth. "Sylvia in Devon, 1962"
      See: Box 4, folder 123
    - Steiner, Nancy Hunter. "Sylvia Plath: A Roommate's Memoir": printed version 1973 Jan (Box-folder 6:150)
    - Stem, Marcia Brown. Diary (excerpt) 1951 Jul 24 (Box-folder 6:151)
    - Vendler, Helen. "Sylvia Plath Playing Pygmalion to Her Own Galatea": printed version from The New York Times Book Review 1971 Oct 10 (Box-folder 6:152)
- Series III. Other Papers, 1918-74
  - Clippings about Sylvia Plath (5 items) 1949-50 (Box-folder 6:153)
  - Clippings about Sylvia Plath at Mademoiselle (1 item) 1953 Aug (Box-folder 6:154)
  - Clippings about "Sylvia Plath" (play) (3 items) 1974 Jan (Box-folder 6:155)
  - Clippings about Sylvia Plath's suicide attempt (9 items) 1953 Aug (Box-folder 6:156)
  - Death certificate of Sylvia Plath: COPY 1963 Feb 11 (Box-folder 6:157)
  - Documents of Plath and Schober families (23 items) 1918-56
    - - Birth certificate for Frank Richard Schober (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Death certificates for Otto Plath, Theodore Plath, and Aurelia Greenwood Schober (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Divorce of Otto and Lydia Plath (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Marriage certificate for Frank and Louise Schober (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Street listings for 892 Shirley St. and 92 Johnson Ave., Winthrop, Massachusetts (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Tax reports for 892 Shirley St. and 92 Johnson Ave., Winthrop (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Voter registrations for Aurelia S. Plath, Frank Schober, and Frank R. Schober (Box-folder 6:158)
    - - Winthrop Cemetery Plot Record (Box-folder 6:158)
  - Obituaries of Sylvia Plath (3 items) 1963 (Box-folder 6:159)
  - School notes of Sylvia Plath for "The Novelist & the Unknown": photocopy undated (Box-folder 6:160)
- Series IV. Photographs, 1949-62
  - Photographs of Sylvia Plath, her children, places she lived, her grave, Otto Plath's grave, and Wellesley High Track Team (15 items) 1949-62 (Box-folder 6:161)